<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Little Giving Journal</title>
    <link>https://journal.littlegiving.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Little Giving Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://journal.littlegiving.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Imam Ghazali on the excellence of sadaqah</title>
      <link>https://journal.littlegiving.org/ghazali/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journal.littlegiving.org/ghazali/</guid>
      <description>Among the hadith [on the excellence of sadaqah, are the following]: The Messenger (sallallahu alayhi wa-sallam) said, &amp;ldquo;Give in charity, though it be only a single date, for it satisfies the hungry and extinguishes sins just as water extinguishes fire.&amp;rdquo; (Ibn Mubarak)
And he (sallallahu alayhi wa-sallam) said, &amp;ldquo;Beware of the fire, if only [by giving] half a date [in charity] and if you lack even that, then by a kind word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A network for distributing daily vegetables in rural India</title>
      <link>https://journal.littlegiving.org/india-veg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journal.littlegiving.org/india-veg/</guid>
      <description>Charity Fatimah have set up a network for distributing a daily subsistence of vegetables in poor areas of West Bengal, to facilitate daily sadaqah on behalf of donors.
The trust based in Forest Gate (London) distributes vegetables across 60 villages in eight districts of West Bengal. A network of local maktabs (elementary schools for learning to read the Quran) sort the vegetables and help facilitate distribution to recipient homes.
Many villagers, in the areas where the trust works, live below the poverty line (25p a day) and stay in makeshift huts made of wood and plastic sheeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing clean water for Helani Village, Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://journal.littlegiving.org/tanzania-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journal.littlegiving.org/tanzania-water/</guid>
      <description>Waterfall have drilled a borehole and installed a pump and filter system to supply Helani Village in Tanzania with clean water, on behalf of Little Giving users.
Helani is a rural village located in Tanga, eight hours drive from Dar es Salaam. About 500 households (2,000 people) and a mosque benefit from the installation. The system can supply 10,000 litres of water a day and is built to last at least 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A daily bread scheme for widows in Kabul, Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://journal.littlegiving.org/afghanistan-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://journal.littlegiving.org/afghanistan-bread/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few months Mothers of Afghanistan have been facilitating daily bread distribution in Kabul, on behalf of Little Giving users.
Mothers of Afghanistan is a UK registered charity (1190531) that works in Kabul, Jalalabad, Paktika and other areas of Afghanistan.
In Kabul, Mothers of Afghanistan have set up a bread voucher scheme for poor families and widows. Families are assessed and given vouchers which they can use to collect freshly baked bread from local bakeries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
